Claudiu Petre | Software Engineer

LinkedIn: <u>claudiu-p</u> Github: Claudiu-Petre

+44 7721-058-463 claudiu.gpetre@gmail.com

CLAU-HUB

Profile

A committed Sofware Engineer with 2+ years of experience in software development. Aiming to actively contribute to the growth of an organization where my analytical and technical skills could be utilised to the fullest extent. As an Software Engineer I am determined to build and expand my IT skills and experience by assimilating and implementing the latest cutting-edge devlopment tools and procedures.

Experience

Full-stack Software Engineer - Trainee, 'Command Shift' Bootcamp, Manchester, June 2022 - January 2023

'Command Shift' is one of the leading software engineer bootcamps in North of England. It provides an excellent curriculum that builds up a comprehensive understanding and practical skills to enhance innovative software solutions development. The course is led and taught by industry professionals using modern tech principles, through a variety of methods as live lectures, mod sessions, paired programming, self-learning assignments and drop-off sessions.

The skills gained throughout the course:

- Planning and developing new ideas and solutions in a collaborative environment with tutors and peers via brainstorming, code reviews, stand-ups;
- Effective communicating and synergistic efforts through paired programming and group projects throughout the software development lifecycle;
- Designing and creating front-end applications linked to back-end via Express.JS APIs, SQL database and CRUD operations.
- Developing resourcefulness during personal study and coding sessions by researching, filtering and implementing the most effective solutions;
- Continuing personal development and pursue additional certification with guidance from experienced mentors;

CLAU HUB

This platform represents the commitment for meticulously engineering, creative developing and actively management of a professional online portfolio. Its sleek design, responsive architecture and intuitive features, collectively position it as an excellent showcase of the development of my technical proficiency, professional profile and capabilities.

- Impeccable User Experience: Designed with an emphasis on user experience, it is aesthetically pleasing, intuitive and responsive, ensuring seamless functionality across various platforms due to Media Queries.
- Front-End Expertise: The front-end approach, using React.JS (React Icons, Email JS, useRef, useState, JSX syntax) and CSS3, enables implementation of animation, data biding and dynamic rendering, high-quality visuals, direct links to Live Demo and Github repos.
- Back-end Expertise: The back-end side of the projects presented in the website rely on RESTful APIs integration for real-time data retrieval enhancing content management eficiency and also on my own Express.Js (controllers, models, routes) developments. The TDD is ensured by Jest Chai and Mocha.
- **Optimized Performance:** The optimization is ensured through Webpack by reducing loading times, image and file compression.
- Efficient Communication: An easily accessible contact form and integrated social media links facilitated seamless communication, enabling prospective clients, collaborators and visitors to reach out effortlessly.
- **CI/CD:** The website was managed within a Git Version Control System, with continuous integration pipelines in place for smooth deployment on the Netlify platform. Effortless synchronization and automatic deployments were triggered upon pushing updates to the disignated GitHub repository.

Work history

Site Manager, Brackenhill Primary School (UK) November 2021 - present

- Used Smartlog V5- cloud based Fire and H & S compliance management software;
- Managed the Maintenance and Cleaning team (8 people);
- Liaised with a variety of suppliers and contractors for on rolling projects.

PCV Driver, First Yorkshire Group (UK) July 2014 - October 2021

- Delivered company's services to clients and liaised with third parties;
- Attended professional development training programme;

Career Adviser, Close to YOUth Association (RO) June 2009 - August 2012

- Designed career orientation curriculum in accordance with project objectives ;
- Delivered one to one and group career orientation sessions;

Skills

Javascript

React

HTML CSS

Express.Js

SOL- MySOL

TDD Jest

Python

Agile methodologies

Debugging

Docker

GITHub

Postman

CI/CD

Self Motivated

Resilient

Details focused

Problem solving

Analytical
Team Communication

Good sense of humour

Education

Full Stack Engineer,

'Command Shift' Bootcamp, Manchester, 2023

GCSEs,

English (A); Maths (B); Leeds City College

M. B. A.,

Craiova University

B. Ec. Management,

Craiova University

Certification

The Complete **Javascript** (300 hrs), Udemy; 2022

React - Beginners (2

The Complete Python

hrs), Udemy; 2023

Pro Bootcamp (100

days); in progress